Atish Pandav

Hayward, CA, USA

🛮 4153413952 | 🗷 atishpanday1@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/atishpanday | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/atishpanday

Personal Profile_

A student of Statistics, specializing in C++, Javascript and Python Programming, having 2 years of experience as a software engineer working in various fields from frontend development to backend development, database management, as well as DevOps. Accomplished researcher in the field of machine learning and complex systems, IITian with a masters in Physics.

Work Experience

California State University, East Bay

Hayward, CA, USA Jan 2023 - May 2023

SCAA Tutor

• Conducted tutoring sessions in Physics, Mathematics, and Computing for students.

- Facilitated online classes to ensure a comprehensive understanding of subject matter and improved academic performance.
- Skills: Physics, Mathematics, Computer Science

Wisestep Hyderabad, India

Full Stack Engineer Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

- Implemented test-driven development for microservices APIs, enhancing efficiency by 20% and reducing API errors by 15%.
- · Spearheaded the migration of legacy front-end code to React.js, boosting website performance and increasing user engagement by 30%.
- Ensured consistent and high-quality user experience in collaboration with UI/UX designers, resulting in a 25% decrease in user complaints and a 15% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Developed modular and intuitive user interfaces, aligning with the evolution of the Design System for efficient web application development.
- Translated product design and wireframes into code, emphasizing performance and usability while contributing to the foundational blocks of the Design System.
- Skills: Java, Typescript/Javascript, Elasticsearch, Kafka, PostgreSQL, Docker, Linux, React.js, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Mockito, Redux, AWS.

Daffodil Health Hyderabad, India

Full Stack Engineer (Lead)

Oct 2020 - Oct 2021

- · Developed and led a team of 5 developers in the successful creation and launch of a front-end mobile app using React Native, Ionic React, and Capacitor, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement within the first month.
- · Implemented high-performance back-end code using Node.js, resulting in an average response time of less than 100 milliseconds and handling over 10,000 concurrent requests per minute.
- · Designed an efficient database architecture using PostgreSQL that allowed for seamless data storage and retrieval, reducing query response time by 50% and improving overall app performance.
- Skills: Javascript, React. js, React Native, Ionic, Capacitor, Node. js, Spring Boot, Java, Google Appengine, AWS, PostgreSQL, Express. js.

Education

California State University, East Bay

Hayward, CA, USA

MS in Statistics - Data Science

Aug 2022 - Current

- Working as a SCAA Tutor
- Relevant Courses: Deep Learning, Statistical Theory, Analysis of Variance Models, Statistical Learning, Natural Language Processing

Indian Institute of Technology, Indore

Indore, India

MSc in Physics

Jul 2019 - Jun 2021 Published a paper on machine learning techniques applied to complex system analyses

• Relevant Courses: C++, Pattern Recognition, Complex Systems, Machine Learning, Computer Simulations

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

Ranchi India

BSc in Physics

Jul 2016 - Jun 2019

- · First Class with Distinction
- Relevant Courses: Unix and C Programming, Java, Data Structures and Algorithms, CAD, LABView

Skills

Technical Skills

Node.js, Front-End Development, Back-End Web Development, Software Development, JavaScript, Typescript, Redux.js, Web Application Development, Database Integration, Web Application Architecture, Design Patterns, Testing Methodologies, RESTful APIs, Microservices, GIT, Agile Methodologies, Cloud-Based Architecture, Cloud Deployment, Hybrid Development, HTML, CSS, React.js, Angular, Vue.js, Responsive Design, Web Performance Optimization, UI/UX Design, Browser Developer Tools Fast Learner, Effective Communication, Problem-solving, Adaptability, Time Management, Critical Thinking, Perfectionist,

Soft Skills

Creativity, Commitment to Continuous Learning

FEBRUARY 26, 2024

Projects

Codenames App Hayward, CA, USA

California State University, East Bay

Jan 2024 - Feb 2024

- Implemented the famous board game Codenames on a web app using React.js, MUI and Flask.
- Used NLP and DETECT (Ref.) algorithms to generate clues for the words used in Codenames.
- Skills: React.js, react-spring, Material UI, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Flask, NLTK, Fasttext

2048 Game Hayward, CA, USA

California State University, East Bay

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

- Implemented the popular 2048 game on web using React.js and transitions using react-spring.
- · Link to the game
- Skills: React.js, react-spring, Material UI, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Kuramoto Model in CUDA Indore, India

Indian Institute of Technology, Indore

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

- Implemented CUDA parallel computing for Kuramoto oscillator equations, enhancing accuracy with a 4th-order Runge-Kutta method and achieving a 1000% speed increase for large networks.
- Skills: C++, CUDA, GPU Programming, OOP, Parallel programming.

Graph Classification using CNN

Indore, India

Indian Institute of Technology, Indore

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

- Efficiently classified diverse graph types using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), analyzed time-series data from the Kuramoto Model with MATLAB, and conducted high-performance network simulations in C++.
- Skills: Python, CNN, C++, MATLAB, Time-series analysis, Kuramoto oscillators, Simultaneous differential equations, Runge-Kutta methods.

Twitter Data Analysis Indore, India

Indian Institute of Technology, Indore

Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Analyzed millions of tweets, created a network using tweet mentions, and identified a 20% spread of Covid-19-related rumors in the Twitter network.
- Skills: Python, Data extraction, Data analysis, Twitter API, Network analysis, Networkx.

Equivalent Resistance Calculator

Ranchi, India

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

Jan 2019 - Jul 2019

- Developed a C++ program employing nodal analysis to determine the equivalent resistance between two junctions, calculate potentials at each junction, and ascertain the current flow through all the wires.
- Skills: C++, Nodal analysis, OOP, Mesh analysis.

Publications

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

Machine learning assisted network classification from symbolic time-series Atish Panday, Woo Seok Lee, Shubhasanket Dutta, Sarika Jalan

Chaos 31 (Mar. 2021). 2021

Achievements

2023	Runner up, CSU East Bay Gradslam	USA
2021	315/340 , Graduate Record Examinations (GRE)	India
2019	All India Rank - 370, Joint Admission for Masters Exam	India
2018	Rank - 3, Chess Championship at BIT Mesra	India
2016	All India Rank - 19000, IIT-JEE Advanced	India
2011	97 percentile, Yukti National Exam	India

Languages

English Professional proficiencyHindi Native proficiencyBengali Native proficiencySpanish Beginner

FEBRUARY 26, 2024